

1610 - 50 Thomas Riley Road, Etobicoke, ON, M9B 0C5

■ jayparikh1996@gmail.com | 🛅 /in/jayparikh1996

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Objective

Detail oriented Physics graduate and Microsoft Certified Lead IT professional hopeful for the position of Power Apps Developer to apply 4 years of experience in system development and analysis looking to join a team focused on quality and efficiency. A team player with strong system development, data analysis, trouble shooting and communication skills.

Work Experience _____

AlarmTek Smart Security

Saskatoon, Sk

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Sept. 2020 - Current

Jan. 2018 - Sept. 2020

October 2018

- Independently worked on the migration of legacy applications to current Microsoft technologies.
- Design backend databases, front end user interfaces and logical layers as per the business requirements using Agile methodology.
- Collaborate with Marketing and sales team to create canvas app for quick quote estimate. Simplified the Customer Service and Field Service model driven app for its optimum use as per requirement.
- Work with accounting department to simplify the billing process by Building complex calculative canvas app, along with automating the process of ordering the products and sending work order copy to customer using Power Automate and Power Apps. Also, part of my job is to maintain the smooth operation of the developed systems.
- Assist with documentation and training module of the developed system, along with analysing and resolving technical and application problems among different departments throughout the company.
- · Identify and encourage area for growth and improvement within team by simplifying current process using PowerApps.
- Creating dashboards for data analysis using Power BI. e.g., Dashboards to track daily leads, sales and detailed report of Inventory for Marketing and Billing department.

University of Regina Regina, Sk

• Designed an experiment for automatic gain correction procedure of SiPM

Data acquisition using CAEN

STUDENT RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- Analysis and visualisation of large data set using c++
- Machine learning using Python
- · Technical writing and presentation with LaTex and PowerPoint

University of Regina Regina, Sk

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Jan. 2018 - Sept. 2020

- Teaching Physics Labs to undergraduate students.
- Completed and filed all necessary paperwork for classroom activities, including attendance logs.
- Supported instructor with test administration and assignment grading.
- · Encouraged dynamic and pleasant educational environment by promoting both gentle discipline and positive student behavior.
- Worked with individual students to provide personalized educational, behavioral and emotional support.

University of Regina Regina, Sk

• Help school students to perform hands on experiment for Fall open house

• Guide students to take informed decision and solve their query about pursuing physics degree

Certifications

VOLUNTEER

Microsoft Etobicoke, ON

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: POWER PLATFORM FUNDAMENTALS

Jan. 2022

Microsoft Etobicoke, ON

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE AI FUNDAMENTALS Sept. 2021

APRIL 15, 2022 JAY PARIKH · RESUME 1

- Linux operating system
- · Microsoft Power Platform
- Microsoft Azure
- · Microsoft Power BI
- Google Analytics
- Google Tag Manager
- Monte Carlo Simulation
- C/C++
- Python
- LaTex

Education

University Of Regina Regina, Sk

MASTER OF SCIENCE (PHYSICS)

Jan. 2018 - Sept. 2020

- · Thesis: The development of PET imaging system capable of improved image quality and increased detector sensitivity
- · Graduated with 80%

St. Xavier's College Ahmedabad, GJ

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (PHYSICS)

- June 2014 April 2017
- · Graduated with GPA:4

Co-curricular Activities

TRUIMF Vancouver

SUMMER STUDENT

Aug 2018

· Participated in Graduate Instrumentation and Detector School 2018

• Project: Size effect on melting temperature of nano particle

St. Xavier's college Gujarat, India

RESEARCH FELLOW

2017

• I got selected by Physics department and worked on "Size effect on melting temperature of nano particles" under the guidance of Dr. Tushar Pandya.

Indian association of Physics teacher

Punjab, India

PRESENTATION SPEAKER

November 2016

• Presented my research work "Size effect on melting temperature of nano particles"

Institute for Plasma Research

PARTICIPANT

Gujarat, India 2015, 2016

- Participated actively in National Science day Celebration
- · I have done a project on "To be friend with Radioactivity" and "Cloud Chamber model" under the supervision of Dr.Cvs Rao and Dr.Tejen Basu in 2015 and 2016 respectively.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2018	UR Graduate Research Award,	Regina, Sk
2018	FGSR Master graduate teaching assistanceship,	Regina, Sk
2018	UR Graduate Scholarship,	Regina, Sk
2019	UR Graduate Scholarship,	Regina, Sk
2019	UR Graduate Research Award,	Regina, Sk
2020	UR Graduate Scholarship,	Regina, Sk
2020	UR Graduate Research Award.	Reging, Sk

DOMESTIC

2017 Gold Medal and Scholarship for excellent work in Research, Ahmedabad, GJ